Errietta Kostala | CV

London E14

I am a senior developer with 5 years of experience and skills in Node.JS, Perl, React, and AWS. I am experienced in designing reliable systems, integrating with third parties, and modernising legacy code bases, as well as building modern solutions from the ground up. I am an extremely motivated person who learns rapidly and adapts to a wide range of technologies. I do not stick to only a single tool or programming language; in fact I choose the right tool for the job and quickly adapt to new technology stacks.

Key skills

- Node.JS / Typescript
- Perl
- React
- AWS / Heroku
- Microservices
- o Functional Programming
- o Test-Driven Development
- o Relational databases (Postgres, MySQL)
- NoSQL (Mongodb)
- o Git

Employment History

FairFX PLC London

Software Architect (Senior Node.js/Perl developer)

2016 – Present

- Database Design

The FairFX corporate platform provides prepaid debit cards for employee expenses. Historically, FairFX integrated with a single company to issue these cards, and the FairFX data model was designed to match the model of that issuer. However, a need arose to be able to integrate with two other issuers in addition to the already existing one.

I re-designed part of the database schema so that it used an issuer-agnostic model and was able to hold data for new features such as multi-currency cards. I was also involved in creating and carrying out a migration plan which seamlessly converted the data for all of our 600000 customers to this new format.

Microservices

Developed and deployed Node.js/Typescript microservice applications to AWS, including a Microservice that took data from an SQS queue and fetched prepaid card balances for thousands of users at a time, and microservices that reported on products ordered in a defined time period.

- RESTful APIs

Worked on designing and developing REST API features for both internal and partner use. The API features I was involved in include decrypting and presenting a customer's card PIN, making payments for orders, and displaying transaction information.

- Security improvements

Took initiative in finding and fixing security issues with our platforms, such as Cross-site scripting and SQL injection, as well as following a third party agency's recommendations to keep us PCI compliant.

- Technical Specification

Created technical specifications and software design for two different projects: one was agreeing on an API for a partner that needed access to our software platform, and the other was our integration with a new prepaid card issuer.

Skills: Perl, Node.JS, Typescript, AWS, PostgreSQL

Self-Employed Remote

Freelancer 2013 - 2016

Mobile application development

I developed an e-leaning mobile video player for a client. The application handled user log-ins, allowed users to play and download course videos, as well as bookmarking and rating videos.

- Web app development

I developed a personal expense / budgeting system (hyperbudget.net) which can parse CSV exports of bank statement and categorise transactions based on a pre-defined set of rules given by the user.

- Mentoring

Acted as a professional mentor for new developers (codementor.io) and helped them learn technologies such as Javascript/Node.js and PHP, as well as giving career advice. On this platform, I consistently maintained a 4.9/5 star rating.

Skills: Node.JS, Typescript, MongoDB, Ionic, Angular, React, Client communication

Shadowcat Systems Consultancy

Lancaster

2014 - 2015

Software Developer

- Payment processing

I led the Paypal integration for a SaaS platform for a client (ShadowNMS). This involved taking one-off as well as recurring payments, and ensuring that only subscribed users could access the platform, as well as linking different platform features to different subscription tiers.

Android Application Development

Developed a native android application for a local rewards scheme called the Barter Project.

- E2E Testing

E2E/Black-box testing of a payment provider API for Paysafe Group (then known as Optimal Payments) as well as technical writing and improving documentation. The project involved ensuring all API endpoints worked as documented, and correcting documentation when it was wrong.

Skills: Perl, Javascript, Cordova, Client communication

Volunteer work / Open Source contributions

o Mozilla Webmaker Improved Mozilla's online platform for learning Web development called Webmaker, making it work offline for slower/mobile connections.

Skills: Javascript, Angular, React

- Firefox for Mobile (Fennec) Made small bug fixes and improvements on the Firefox mobile application for Android. Skills: Java
- o freenode (IRC network) Worked as one of freenode's volunteer user support staff, answering users' questions. In addition to this, I developed fixes and new features for their IRC server software.

Skills: Communication, Perl, C

o Code Club Taught children aged 9 - 11 the basics of programming using a drag-and-drop development tool called Scratch. Skills: Mentoring, Communication

Talks

- Introduction to modern Javascript London June 2018 https://erk.im/es6
- Perl dependency management London October 2017 https://erk.im/carton
- Catalyst VS Mojolicious Amsterdam August 2017 https://erk.im/mojo

Education

Huddersfield University Huddersfield

BSc (Hons) Web Technologies, First Class